Rafli Purnama Putra

Bogor, West Java, 16913 | 0813-8634-0084 | rafliprnm@gmail.com | https://portofolio-rafliprnm.vercel.app/

PROFILE

With more than one year of experience in website development at the Directorate of Information Technology Center Telkom University, I became a Front-End Developer, where I was responsible for creating HTML, CSS and TypeScript code using the Angular framework. Additionally, I also took on the role of Quality Assurance Specialist, where my responsibilities included understanding project goals, designing test cases and scenarios, and conducting thorough application testing while reporting identified bugs.

EDUCATION

Universitas Telkom 2020 – 2024

Major in Information Technology - GPA: 3.86 out of 4.00 (Cumlaude)

LBPP LIA 2018 – 2019

Intermediate Level

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Direktorat Pusat Teknologi Informasi Telkomuniversity

Quality Assurance | contract

Oct 2023 - Now

- Conduct comprehensive testing of web applications to identify and document defects, inconsistencies, and usability issues.
- Testing the API with postman.
- Provide suggestions and recommendations for error or bug fixes.
- Create test plans, strategies and test cases based on project requirements.
- Report and track identified issues containing bugs, and discuss them with developers to resolve them.

Direktorat Pusat Teknologi Informasi Telkomuniversity

Front End Web Developer | contract

Oct 2022 - Oct 2023

- Implementing user interfaces and interactive elements using HTML, CSS, and TypeScript to make websites responsive and engaging.
- Identifying and resolving issues, bugs, or inconsistencies in the front-end code.
- Work closely with back-end developers to ensure seamless integration of front-end and back-end components.
- Provide guidance to interns to ensure successful completion of their assignments.

ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCE

Informatics Lab Telkomuniversity

lab assistant

Dec 2021 – July 2022

- Provides comprehensive theoretical material and relevant practical training to ensure in-depth understanding and direct application of the concepts taught.
- Assist practicum participants in completing practice questions by providing advice and guidance.
- Check and correct the results of practicum participants' practice questions.

Chevalier ab Telkomuniversity

Web Division Member Dec 2021 – Sep 2022

• Actively participate in study groups dedicated to exploration and in-depth learning in the field of web development, sharing knowledge and improving skills among its members.

COURSE & CERTIFICATION

| • | <u>Learn the Basics of Web Programming</u> by Dicoding | July 2022 |
|---|---|-----------|
| • | <u>Learn to Create a Web Front-End for Beginners</u> by Dicoding | July 2022 |
| • | Full Stack Web Developer by BuildWithAngga | July 2022 |
| • | Complete Beginner QA Engineer: E2E Testing with Cypress by BuildWithAngga | Feb 2023 |

PUBLICATION

KINETIK: Game Technology, Information System, Computer Network, Computing, Electronics, and Control | Sinta 2 The Website Quality Analysis Using Modified Webqual Method and Importance Performance Analysis on SITU TAK Website | https://doi.org/10.22219/kinetik.v9i1.1866 | Feb 2024

SKILLS & TOOLS

| ● Jira | • | HTML & CSS | • | Research |
|----------------------------|---|------------|---|------------------------|
| Trello | • | Typescript | • | Communication |
| Qase.io | • | Angular | • | Teamwork |
| Postman | • | Cypress | • | English (Intermediate) |
| | | | | |